

ASPIRING SOFTWARE ENGINEER

□ (+1) 408-667-4711 | ■ daniel.budziwojski@gmail.com | 🛅 daniel-budziwojski

Summary_

Inquisitive and persevering full-stack developer with hands-on experience in various technologies. Contributed to open source projects and volunteered on developing a public health app. Strong team player that delivers under pressure in an agile environment.

Education

University of Southern California - GPA: 3.96, Dean's List for 2 semesters

Los Angeles, CA

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug 2020 - May 2023

Coursework: Algorithms and the Theory of Computing, Data Structures, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Systems (x86), Embedded Systems, Software Engineering, Object Oriented Design, Discrete Mathematics, Operating Systems (Planned Spring 2022), Internetworking (Planned Spring 2022)

San Jose State University - GPA: 4.0, President's Scholar for all semesters

San Jose, CA

COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug 2019 - May 2020

Experience _____

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Playa Vista, CA

Feb 2021 - Present

- Designed new OpenTutor admin features with a TypeScript ReactJS front-end, GraphQL back-end, and a NoSQL database to generate and export data in CSV, PDF, and other proprietary formats.
- Spearheaded development of a new learning mode, the addition of multiple interactive media options to lessons, and the redesign of older pages in a mobile-first paradigm.
- Created responsive bulk data editors with filters, regex searching, and implemented cursor-based server-side pagination.
- Developed a node testing framework for mocking complex GraphQL calls for internal use in CI/CD pipeline.
- Implemented a new dialog system in a flask-RESTful application.

USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Playa Vista, CA

RELI INTERN

May 2020 - Aug 2020

- Worked on the OpenTutor team, in designing an open-source research project intended to scale up dialog-based tutoring by enabling ordinary teachers to rapidly author and improve dialog-based intelligent tutoring systems.
- Designed and implemented web-based mobile-first clients for OpenTutor system using ReactJS (with Redux) and Gatsby frameworks with MaterialUI components and GraphQL queries. This included approachable user-friendly UIs and powerful, yet intuitive, teaching interfaces.
- Developed full end-to-end tests utilizing Cypress, snapshot tests with Percy, and deployed onto AWS with Docker containers.
- Prototyped a mobile client with React Native for internal consumption.

Kingdom Brick Supply LLC

Sunnyvale, CA

FOUNDER-CHIEF OPERATING OFFICER

Jun 2015 - Present

- Founded company selling LEGO products and display cases.
- Developed a full multi-tier business applications consisting of front-end clients written in Swift, Java, and PHP, a middle tier REST API in Java, and a persistence layer using relational databases.
- Worked with developers, APIs, and SDKs from companies such as Apple and IPC Mobile to integrate multi-platform applications supported by their software and hardware.
- Implemented OIDC and SAML SSO for login into company applications.

Volunteer Projects

FindMyVaxSC

Santa Clara, CA 95051

i iliality vaxo

LEAD PROGRAMMER Mar 2021 - Aug 2021

- Built a web-based tool enabling eligible people to find access to a COVID-19 vaccine in the SF Bay Area by pooling data from hundreds of locations, such as healthcare providers, pharmacies, city-run programs, and state sites.
- Designed app to be lightweight and localized with i18n libraries to remain accessible to everyone especially in under-served communities.

Skills

Languages Java, C/C++, React, Swift, Python, PHP

Frameworks REST, GraphQL, ReactJS, React Native, Gatsby, Jersey, JAX-RS, Hibernate

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Testing Cypress, Percy, Detox, Cucumber, GitHub Actions, CircleCI

Deployment Env AWS, Docker

Methodologies Scrum, Test Driven Development

Others HTML, CSS, JS, TS, Git